eatlocalgrown.com 2019-12-25

# Privacy Policy

**Privacy Policy**  
Last Updated on: November, 2018

Eat Local Grown (hereafter referred to as ELG) is committed to protecting the privacy of visitors to our website, subscribers to our newsletters, and those providing contact information. In addition, ELG is opposed to unauthorized commercial e-mail delivery, otherwise known as spam. Please read the following Privacy and Spam Policy to understand how your personal information is treated. From time to time, ELG may offer new information or services that may affect this policy. If you have any questions or concerns regarding this Privacy and Spam Policy, please send an e-mail to [ ](mailto:%20%3Cscript%20type='text/javascript'%3E%20%3C!--%20var%20prefix%20=%20'ma'%20+%20'il'%20+%20'to';%20var%20path%20=%20'hr'%20+%20'ef'%20+%20'=';%20var%20addy28254%20=%20'privacy'%20+%20'@';%20addy28254%20=%20addy28254%20+%20'eatlocalgrown'%20+%20'.'%20+%20'com';%20document.write\('%3Ca%20'%20+%20path%20+%20'\\''%20+%20prefix%20+%20':'%20+%20addy28254%20+%20'\\'%3E'\);%20document.write\(addy28254\);%20document.write\('%3C\\/a%3E'\);%20//--%3E\\n%20%3C/script%3E%3Cscript%20type='text/javascript'%3E%20%3C!--%20document.write\('%3Cspan%20style=\\'display:%20none;\\'%3E'\);%20//--%3E%20%3C/script%3EThis%20email%20address%20is%20being%20protected%20from%20spambots.%20You%20need%20JavaScript%20enabled%20to%20view%20it.%20%3Cscript%20type='text/javascript'%3E%20%3C!--%20document.write\('%3C/'\);%20document.write\('span%3E'\);%20//--%3E%20%3C/script%3E.)[privacy@eatlocalgrown.com](mailto:privacy@eatlocalgrown.com). Spam abuses can be notified at [ ](mailto:%20%3Cscript%20type='text/javascript'%3E%20%3C!--%20var%20prefix%20=%20'ma'%20+%20'il'%20+%20'to';%20var%20path%20=%20'hr'%20+%20'ef'%20+%20'=';%20var%20addy31802%20=%20'abuse'%20+%20'@';%20addy31802%20=%20addy31802%20+%20'eatlocalgrown'%20+%20'.'%20+%20'com';%20document.write\('%3Ca%20'%20+%20path%20+%20'\\''%20+%20prefix%20+%20':'%20+%20addy31802%20+%20'\\'%3E'\);%20document.write\(addy31802\);%20document.write\('%3C\\/a%3E'\);%20//--%3E\\n%20%3C/script%3E%3Cscript%20type='text/javascript'%3E%20%3C!--%20document.write\('%3Cspan%20style=\\'display:%20none;\\'%3E'\);%20//--%3E%20%3C/script%3EThis%20email%20address%20is%20being%20protected%20from%20spambots.%20You%20need%20JavaScript%20enabled%20to%20view%20it.%20%3Cscript%20type='text/javascript'%3E%20%3C!--%20document.write\('%3C/'\);%20document.write\('span%3E'\);%20//--%3E%20%3C/script%3E.)[abuse@eatlocalgrown.com](mailto:abuse@eatlocalgrown.com).

WHAT INFORMATION DO WE COLLECT & HOW IS IT USED?

Information You Voluntarily Submit to the Website: We may collect personal information from you such as your name or e-mail address. For example, you may voluntarily submit personal information to ELG by leaving a comment, subscribing to a newsletter, or submitting a contact form. In addition, upon making certain purchases described herein, we may ask you to create a user profile, which would allow you to create a username and password. We will store the username, but your password will not be visible in our records.

Information We Collect from Others: We may receive information about you from other sources. For example, if you use a third-party software through the site, they may transfer information to us for fulfillment.

Automatically-Collected Information: We automatically collect certain information about you and the device with which you access ELG. For example, when you use ELG, we will log your IP address, operating system type, browser type, referring website, pages you viewed, and the dates/times when you accessed the website. We may also collect information about actions you take when using ELG, such as links clicked.

Cookies: We may log information using cookies, which are small data files stored on your browser by ELG. We may use both session cookies, which expire when you close your browser, and persistent cookies, which stay on your browser until deleted, to provide you with a more personalized experience on the website.

The following list includes examples of specific ways we collect personal information from our website visitors and the type of information collected:

Electronic Newsletter: To register online for our electronic newsletters, we request the following required information: (i) name, and (ii) e-mail address. The provision of an e-mail address is mandatory in order to receive our newsletter.

Contact Forms: To contact ELG for the purposes of evaluating or engaging our services or to answer your questions, we utilize numerous forms throughout our site. Required information varies depending on the form and at most includes (i) name, and (ii) e-mail address. The provision of this information is mandatory in order to receive a response from ELG. The provision of the remaining information requested on the registration form is optional.

HOW YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION MAY BE USED

ELG may use your personal information in the following ways:

To operate and maintain the website;  
To create your account, identify you as a user of the website, and customize the website to your account;  
To send you promotional information, such as newsletters. Each e-mail newsletter will provide information on how to opt-out of future mailings by unsubscribing;  
To send you administrative communications, such as administrative e-mails, confirmation e-mails, technical notices, updates on policies, or security alerts;  
To respond to your comments or inquiries;  
To provide you with user support;  
To track and measure website performance;  
To process payment for purchases you make through ELG;  
To protect, investigate, and deter against unauthorized or illegal activity;  
To review the effectiveness of our marketing programs and analyse other general demographic trends;  
To notify you of new information or services that may be of interest to you; or,  
To send promotional materials.

DOES ELG SHARE MY INFORMATION?

ELG will not share, rent, or sell your personally identifiable information with third-parties. We may, however, share your information with third-parties when we are authorized to share such information.

Additionally, ELG may use third-party service providers to service various aspects of the website. Each third-party service provider’s use of your personal information is dictated by their respective privacy policy. ELG currently uses the following third-party service providers:

Tracking: ELG uses various marketing tools that help us create a better user experience for people visiting our site. These tools allow us to look at aggregated data such as scrolling patterns, clicks, and allow us to run tests to determine which pages result in the best actions. However, your personally identifiable information is not used by any of these tools. We use the following third-party service providers for tracking:

GetResponse: [Privacy policy](https://www.getresponse.com/legal/privacy.html)

Google Analytics: [Privacy Policy](http://eatlocalgrown.com/Privacy%20Policy)

Remarketing: ELG uses remarketing tracking cookies and conversion pixels from vendors such as Google and Facebook to present special offers to you for our products or services over the Google Content Network and via social networks. This means you may see an ad for one of our products or services as a result of visiting our website. In addition, ELG uses custom audiences based on e-mails of subscribers and customers. This allows us to present special offers for our products and services to you via Facebook. However, your personally identifiable information is not used by any remarketing service other than to present you special offers from us. We use the following third-party service providers for remarketing:

Facebook: [Opt-out of Facebook remarketing here](https://www.facebook.com/help/568137493302217)

Google: [Opt-out of Google remarketing here](https://support.google.com/ads/answer/2662922?hl=en)

Newsletters: ELG uses GetResponse as its e-mail service provider. GetResponse collects contact information, distributes our newsletter, and tracks actions you take that assist us in measuring the performance of the website and newsletters. Upon subscription, GetResponse also tracks the pages you visit on the website.

Our newsletters contain tracking pixels. This pixel is embedded in e-mails and allows us an analysis of the success of our newsletters. Because of these tracking pixels, we may see if and when you open an e-mail and which links within the e-mail you click. This behavior is not passed to third-parties. All data submitted at the time of subscription to our newsletter is stored on GetResponse’s servers. [You may access GetResponse’s privacy policy here](https://www.getresponse.com/legal/privacy.html). At any time, you may be removed from our newsletter list by clicking on the unsubscribe button provided in each e-mail.

We may also rely on a third-party service, OptinMonster, to service certain pop-up subscription boxes. Any information collected by OptinMonster is passed through directly to GetResponse and is not stored by any party other than GetResponse.

Contact Information and Website Support: We offer multiple ways to contact ELG, including contact forms, e-mails, and chat. If at any time, you attempt to contact us through a contact form, the information you provide will be stored on our servers

ANONYMOUS DATA

From time to time, we may use anonymous data, which does not identify you alone, or when combined with data from other parties. This type of anonymous data may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses. Examples of this anonymous data may include analytics or information collected from cookies.

PUBLICLY VISIBLE INFORMATION

If you create a user profile on ELG or the Social Media Marketing Society or leave a comment on ELG, certain information may be publicly visible.

COOKIES

ELG uses cookies to: store visitors’ preferences; record user-specific information on what pages users access or visit; ensure that visitors are not repeatedly sent the same banner ads; or customize our content based on visitors’ browser type or other information that the visitor sends. Cookies may also be used by third-party services, such as Google Analytics, as described herein.

In conjunction with our in-house advertising, we use third-party advertising companies to place customized advertisements on the pages you view on the Site (eg Google Adsense). Our third-party advertising companies also separately place or recognize a cookie file on your browser in the course of delivering advertisements to the Site. These companies may use non-personal information collected by the cookies about your visits to the Site and other web sites in order to provide you with advertisements about goods and services of interest to you.

At any time, you may prevent the setting of cookies by the website, by using a corresponding setting of your internet browser and may thus permanently deny the setting of cookies. Furthermore, already set cookies may be deleted at any time via an Internet browser or other software programs. This is possible in all popular Internet browsers. However, if users deactivate the setting of cookies in your Internet browser, not all functions of ELG may be entirely usable.

WHAT IF THERE ARE CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY AND SPAM POLICY?

If we change our Privacy and Spam Policy, we will post those changes on our privacy page at <http://eatlocalgrown.com/privacy-policy> .

RIGHTS RELATED TO YOUR PERSONAL DATA

Opt-out: You may opt-out of future e-mail communications by following the unsubscribe links in our e-mails. You may also notify us at [privacy@eatlocalgrown.com](mailto:privacy@eatlocalgrown.com) to be removed from our mailing list.

Access: You may access the personal information we have about you by submitting a request to [ ](mailto:%20%3Cscript%20type='text/javascript'%3E%20%3C!--%20var%20prefix%20=%20'ma'%20+%20'il'%20+%20'to';%20var%20path%20=%20'hr'%20+%20'ef'%20+%20'=';%20var%20addy71848%20=%20'privacy'%20+%20'@';%20addy71848%20=%20addy71848%20+%20'eatlocalgrown'%20+%20'.'%20+%20'com';%20document.write\('%3Ca%20'%20+%20path%20+%20'\\''%20+%20prefix%20+%20':'%20+%20addy71848%20+%20'\\'%3E'\);%20document.write\(addy71848\);%20document.write\('%3C\\/a%3E'\);%20//--%3E\\n%20%3C/script%3E%3Cscript%20type='text/javascript'%3E%20%3C!--%20document.write\('%3Cspan%20style=\\'display:%20none;\\'%3E'\);%20//--%3E%20%3C/script%3EThis%20email%20address%20is%20being%20protected%20from%20spambots.%20You%20need%20JavaScript%20enabled%20to%20view%20it.%20%3Cscript%20type='text/javascript'%3E%20%3C!--%20document.write\('%3C/'\);%20document.write\('span%3E'\);%20//--%3E%20%3C/script%3E.)[privacy@eatlocalgrown.com](mailto:privacy@eatlocalgrown.com).

Amend: You may contact us at [privacy@eatlocalgrown.com](mailto:privacy@eatlocalgrown.com) to amend or update your personal information.

Forget: In certain situations, you may request that we erase or forget your personal data. To do so, please submit a request to [ ](mailto:%20%3Cscript%20type='text/javascript'%3E%20%3C!--%20var%20prefix%20=%20'ma'%20+%20'il'%20+%20'to';%20var%20path%20=%20'hr'%20+%20'ef'%20+%20'=';%20var%20addy58538%20=%20'privacy'%20+%20'@';%20addy58538%20=%20addy58538%20+%20'eatlocalgrown'%20+%20'.'%20+%20'com';%20document.write\('%3Ca%20'%20+%20path%20+%20'\\''%20+%20prefix%20+%20':'%20+%20addy58538%20+%20'\\'%3E'\);%20document.write\(addy58538\);%20document.write\('%3C\\/a%3E'\);%20//--%3E\\n%20%3C/script%3E%3Cscript%20type='text/javascript'%3E%20%3C!--%20document.write\('%3Cspan%20style=\\'display:%20none;\\'%3E'\);%20//--%3E%20%3C/script%3EThis%20email%20address%20is%20being%20protected%20from%20spambots.%20You%20need%20JavaScript%20enabled%20to%20view%20it.%20%3Cscript%20type='text/javascript'%3E%20%3C!--%20document.write\('%3C/'\);%20document.write\('span%3E'\);%20//--%3E%20%3C/script%3E.)[privacy@eatlocalgrown.com](mailto:privacy@eatlocalgrown.com).

Please note that we may need to retain certain information for recordkeeping purposes or to complete transactions, or when required by law.

SENSITIVE PERSONAL INFORMATION

At no time should you submit sensitive personal information to ELG. This includes your social security number, information regarding race or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious beliefs, health information, criminal background, or trade union memberships. If you elect to submit such information to us, it will be subject to this Privacy and Spam Policy.

CHILDREN’S INFORMATION

ELG does not knowingly collect any personally identifiable information from children under the age of 16. If a parent or guardian believes that ELG has personally identifiable information of a child under the age of 16 in its database, please contact us immediately at [privacy@eatlocalgrown.com](mailto:privacy@eatlocalgrown.com) and we will use our best efforts to promptly remove such information from our records.

SPAM POLICY

ELG is strongly opposed to spam. We will only send e-mail to users that have explicitly requested to receive an e-mail from ELG. Examples may include:

Opt-in subscribers to the ELG Newsletter  
Users that complete a contact form  
All communication will be related and relevant to what you have requested.  
WEB LINKS

ELG contains links to other sites. Please be aware that ELG is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such other sites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site to read the privacy and spam policies of each and every website that collects personally identifiable information. This Privacy and Spam Policy applies solely to information collected by ELG.

HOW DO I CONTACT ELG?

If you have any further questions or comments regarding the ELG website or this Privacy and Spam Policy, you may contact [ ](mailto:%20%3Cscript%20type='text/javascript'%3E%20%3C!--%20var%20prefix%20=%20'ma'%20+%20'il'%20+%20'to';%20var%20path%20=%20'hr'%20+%20'ef'%20+%20'=';%20var%20addy92223%20=%20'privacy'%20+%20'@';%20addy92223%20=%20addy92223%20+%20'eatlocalgrown'%20+%20'.'%20+%20'com';%20document.write\('%3Ca%20'%20+%20path%20+%20'\\''%20+%20prefix%20+%20':'%20+%20addy92223%20+%20'\\'%3E'\);%20document.write\(addy92223\);%20document.write\('%3C\\/a%3E'\);%20//--%3E\\n%20%3C/script%3E%3Cscript%20type='text/javascript'%3E%20%3C!--%20document.write\('%3Cspan%20style=\\'display:%20none;\\'%3E'\);%20//--%3E%20%3C/script%3EThis%20email%20address%20is%20being%20protected%20from%20spambots.%20You%20need%20JavaScript%20enabled%20to%20view%20it.%20%3Cscript%20type='text/javascript'%3E%20%3C!--%20document.write\('%3C/'\);%20document.write\('span%3E'\);%20//--%3E%20%3C/script%3E.)[privacy@eatlocalgrown.com](mailto:privacy@eatlocalgrown.com).

LEGAL DISCLAIMER

We may disclose personal information when required by law or in the good-faith belief that such action is necessary in order to conform to the edicts of the law or comply with a legal process served on our site.

THIS SITE DOES NOT PROVIDE ANY MEDICAL ADVICE

Information on this web site is provided for informational purposes only and is not intended as a substitute for the advice provided by your physician or other healthcare professional or any information contained on or in any product label or packaging. You should not use the information on this web site for diagnosing or treating a health problem or disease, or prescribing any medication or other treatment. You should always speak with your physician or other healthcare professional before taking any medication or nutritional, herbal or homeopathic supplement, or adopting any treatment for a health problem. For any products or services purchased from this web site, you should read carefully all product packaging and instructions. If you have or suspect that you have a medical problem, promptly contact your health care provider. Never disregard professional medical advice or delay in seeking professional advice because of something you have read on this web site. Information provided on this web site and the use of any products or services purchased from our web site by you DOES NOT create a doctor-patient relationship between you and any of the physicians affiliated with our web site. Information and statements regarding dietary supplements have not been evaluated by the Food and Drug Administration and are not intended to diagnose, treat, cure, or prevent any disease.
